Frank E. Canavaciol Papers RG.10
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
Guide to the Frank E. Canavaciol Papers, 1935-1962
Bulk, 1950-1960
RG.10
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
4.0 Cubic feet
The Frank E. Canavaciol Papers contain lecture notes and other course materials from electrical engineering courses taught by Canavaciol during the 1940s, 1950s, and 1960s. This collection also includes materials from Canavaciol's involvement with the Professional Engineer Licensing Examinations, both as a question writer and grader, and other notes and related literature.
Canavaciol, Frank E.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged into four series:
Series I: Electical Engineering Courses Series II: Professional Activities Series III: Relevant Literature Series IV: Miscellaneous
Within Series I, folders are arranged in subseries according the course number and then chronologically. All other series are arranged by subject first, and then chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists primarily of lecture notes, homework problems, and lab experiments from classes taught by Canavaciol from the mid-1930s through the 1950s. During his time at Polytechnic, Canavaciol also submitted and reviewed questions for the Professional Engineer Licensing Exam and his sample questions, answers, original test booklets, and records of his involvement from 1947- 1962 are also present. The collection also contains related literature from Canavaciol’s library, primarily reprints, brochures, and manuals from companies such as AT&T, RCA, and General Electric, though there are also some larger volumes, including a course book from an extension course offered by Westinghouse. Lastly, wire samples from the Sensitive Research Instruments Corporation are also included.
Biographical/Historical note
Frank E. Canavaciol was an instructor of electrical engineering at Polytechnic from 1916 until 1966. He taught a variety of classes in the Electrical Engineering Department, ranging from entry-level 401 and 402 classes to upper level classes. During his time at Polytechnic, he also co-authored a book on the topic of Radio Phone Receiving in 1922, and was an active participant in the Professional Engineering Licensing Exams, helping to both write and review electrical engineering questions. He died in Queens in May of 1987, at the age of 91.
AT & T Bell Laboratories.; General Electric Company.; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.) -- Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.; Polytechnic University (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; RCA Manufacturing Company, inc..; Electrical engineering; Engineering; Laboratory notes; Lecture notes; Reprints; Serials (publications)
- Series I: Electrical Engineering Courses, 1936-1960
  - Subseries A: Early Lecture Notes, 1936-1940
    - Lecture Notes, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Notes, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: EE 401, 1946-1956
    - Labs, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Labs and Notes, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Labs, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: EE 402, 1956
    - Labs, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D: EE 406, 1944-1955
    - Notes, 1944-53, 1944-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries E: EE 408, undated
    - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Subseries F: EE 411, 1952-1959
    - Labs, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Labs, 1953-54, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Notes and Problems, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Notes and Problems, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Problems, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Problems, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Problems, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Notes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Notes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Subseries G: EE 412, 1953-1958
    - Labs, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lab Notes, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Notes and Problems, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Notes and Problems, 1956 (summer) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Notes, 1957 (summer) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Problems, 1957 (summer) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Problems, 1956-1957 (summer) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Problems, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Problems, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Subseries H: EE 413, 1951-1953
    - Notes and Problems, 1951-53, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Labs and Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Subseries I: EE 415, 1959
    - Problems, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Subseries J: EE 421, 1959
    - Problems, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Notes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Subseries K: EE 422, undated
    - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Subseries L: EE 426, 1961
    - Labs, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Subseries M: EE 442, 1949-1953
    - Notes and Labs, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Labs, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Notes, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Problems, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Subseries N: EE 443, undated
    - Notes and Labs, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Subseries O: EE 444, undated
    - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Subseries P: EE 466, undated
    - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Subseries Q: Miscellaneous Couse Materials, undated
    - Miscellaneous Experiments, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Unmarked Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series II: Professional Activities, 1947-1962
  - Subseries A: BTHS Candidate Exams, 1948
    - Candidate Exams for BTHS Electrical Dept Head, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: PE Exams, 1947-1962
    - PE License Exams, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Subseries C: Pro to EE, 1949
      - Pro to EE Questions, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - PE License Exams, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - PE License Exams, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - PE License Exams, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - PE License Exams, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - PE License Exams, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - PE License Exams, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - PE License Exams, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - PE License Exams, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - PE License Exams, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - PE License Exams, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - PE License Exams, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - PE License Exams, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - PE License Exams, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - PE License Exams, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Suggested/Unused Questions, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Out of State PE Exams, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - NCSBEE Annual report appendices, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Series III: Relevant Literature, 1902-1960
  - General Radio Experimenter, 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bridges, 1929-1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Electric, 1927-1948 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - RCA, 1934-1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Loran, Radar, Sonar; 1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bell Telephone Labs, 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Westinghouse, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Varied, 1902 - 1928 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Varied, 1931 - 1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Varied, 1947 - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Varied (bound, not in folder), 1931-1934 (Box 3)
  - AT&T (bound volume, not in folder), 1928 (Box 3)
  - Westinghouse Extension Course (bound, not in folder), 1939 (Box 3)
  - Transistor Specifications (bound, not in folder), 1934 (Box 3)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous, 1935-1955
  - Wire Samples, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Correspondence, 1935- 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)